So let's do a quick cleanup just to make sure
we have a clean slate and that we don't overpay anything
even though we are in the free tier.
So if you go to the EC2 Dashboard, you will see all
the resources running in your region.
So I have two running instances.
I'm going to open this in new tab.
Four volumes and then four key pairs.
You can leave it as is.
It doesn't cost you any money, no matter what.
Snapshots, I have two so I will open this in new tab.
And then finally, security group.
As well, it don't cost you any money so I'm going
to leave them as is.
So for our EC2 instances, you can take them all,
right-click, and then terminate them.
See, this is very easy.
This is the cloud.
Then for the volumes, we have some root EBS volumes
that are going to be deleted as we terminate our instances.
But for these two EBS volumes, I'm going to delete them
as well manually, okay.
And finally, for the snapshots, I can delete
the snapshot right away.
So I can take these two things, do action,
delete the snapshots, yes.
And then it says this one is not being able to be deleted
because it is in use by an AMI.
So I will say okay, go to AMI on the left-hand side.
I'm going to delete the AMI so I can just deregister it.
I say yes, I want to be deregistering this AMI.
And back into our snapshots, now I'm able to get this one,
delete it, and say yes. And now we should be good to go.
So if I look at instances, all terminated.
If I look at EBS volumes, none of them.
And snapshots, empty, and AMI, empty.
Okay, that's it for the cleanup.
I'm going to refresh this and as we can see,
we are good to go.
And I will see you in the next lecture.