Okay, so let's explore the IAM console.
For this, I just type IAM
and I go straight into the IAM console.
So this is where we're going to be managing our account.
And as you can see
from the top right corner, it says Global.
That means that this does not require a region selection
and IAM is a global service.
So no matter where you are,
you will have the same users across all your regions.
That makes sense.
Next, what we're going to do is to go ahead
and create our first users.
So you can disregard any of these messages right now.
Don't worry about them.
And we go under Users and on user,
we're going to add a user.
So why do we need users?
Well, that's because we're using the root account.
If I go on the top right, as you can see,
it just gives me my account ID.
So that means I'm using the root account
and it has too much permissions.
And so what I want to do is instead to create admin users
and regular users and use them within AWS.
So let's go and create our first user.
It's going to be named Stephane,
and I want to provide myself access
to the management console.
As you can see right now, there's an option says,
Hey, do you want to use a user
in Identity Center?
That's the recommended way,
or do you want to create an IAM user?
I'm going to go against the recommendations of AWS
because right now, from an exam perspective,
you need to know about IAM users
and the Identity Center is a bit more complicated to set up.
But don't worry, this does not affect your course
and you will learn everything you need to know for the exam.
So please bear with me
and follow along by creating an IAM user.
So you scroll down
and then you have to have a console password.
Now, if this was for someone else,
I would use an auto-generated password
but because this is for me,
I can just enter a password that I know of.
And you need to make sure that you are complaint
with the rules of the password right here.
Then I can disable this box
because I don't need to create a new password at sign in.
But I would do this
if it was another user I'm creating an account for.
Then you click on Next.
Okay, so next, we need to add a user
to group or attach permissions to it directly.
But we're going to create groups because it's much easier.
So let's create a group.
And this group name is going to be admin.
And the admin group is going to have one policy attached
called AdministratorAccess.
So you take this one, you scroll all the way down
and you click on Create user group.
So now the user can be added to the group admin
and because we will be in this admin group,
we will inherit the policies of that group,
which is AdministratorAccess.
Click on Next. Here we can review and create the user.
As you can see, you have optional tags.
Tags are everywhere in AWS.
They can help to include some extra information
about your data
but they don't impact how your account is functioning.
For example, I could enter a tag
and say that the department of Stephane is engineering.
This is the kind of usage for tags, but again,
it's just information you can add for users, for groups
and pretty much any resources within AWS.
So I will just show you how to do it once
but I won't do it everywhere.
Okay, so let's create this user.
Now, the user is successfully created, and what I can do
is that I can email the sign in instruction.
I can download the CSV to have the username
and the password, or I can click here
and return to the user list.
And now let's explore what we have created.
So under user groups, I will find the group admin
and if I click on it, I can see that there's one user
in this group, which is the Stephane user.
And if I look at the group permissions, as we can see,
there's a policy name attached to the group,
which is the administrator access,
which provides full admin access
to any users within the group.
And so if we go and click on the user, Stephane,
so this is a user you can also get back from this menu
on the left-hand side and just click on user Stephane.
Okay, so if you click on the user, Stephane, back to it.
Okay, great.
We have these permissions, and the permissions associated
with my user is AdministratorAccess
and this is a managed policy that we inherited
from the group admin.
Okay, so we have our users and we have our groups
and now we're going to see how to log in
with that user Stephane.
So to do so, let's go back into the dashboard.
And on the right-hand side of the dashboard,
we have some summary about our AWS account.
So the account ID is right here,
which you can also get by opening this panel.
So this is the same account ID here and here,
and the account alias is what you can set to log in
to your account faster
because remembering numbers sometimes is difficult.
So you can create an account alias
and you just have to specify an alias that you like.
For example, stephane-aws--v2, and click on Save Changes.
Now, this is a unique alias for my account.
You're not gonna be able to use this alias for your account,
but you can create your own.
And now we have a sign in URL
on the right-hand side that is customized for my alias.
So if I click on copy this URL,
I need to open it in a new tab,
but it must be an incognito tab or a different web browser.
So here I've opened a private window in Firefox,
which is going to be a different session.
And so therefore, I can copy you the sign in URL
and paste it here and press enter.
Now we are taken again to the login page of AWS
and as we can see, we have three fields in a row.
We have the account ID, the IAM username, and the password.
So what's happening here is that we, using this URL,
are taken to a sign in page as an IAM user.
And how do we know this?
How can we get back to this page if you wanted to?
Well, when we went into the sign in,
we had two options, either root user
which will log you in as a root user or IAM user
in which case, you just need to enter the account ID
or the account alias.
And then click on Next,
which will take you into the page we had from before,
which was this page right here.
So now in this page,
what I need to do is to enter my IAM username
and the password that I just created,
and then click on sign in.
And we are now logged in as an IAM user in the console.
So how do we know this?
Well, if you're logged in as a root user, as you can see
when you click on the account
it says My account and the account number.
This is a root user.
But if we go on the right-hand side, we can see
that there is Stephane@ and then the account alias.
And so what we can see is that Stephane
is the IAM user Stephane,
and then we're at my accounts and the account number.
So we know on the right-hand side
that we're logged in as an IAM user.
Now, this IAM user can do pretty much anything
that the other user was able to do, the root user
because they're both admins, okay?
But from a course perspective, it's better
if you use an IAM user than using the root account.
Now, you will see in some videos, I have the root user,
in some videos, I have the IAM user.
It doesn't really matter from a course perspective, okay?
So I will use them as I please.
But if I need to use the root user specifically,
I will let you know.
Or if I need to use an IAM user specifically,
I will let you know as well, okay?
But just so you know, to keep on going this section,
please have the root account,
as well as your IAM user ready and available.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.