So let me show you how to create access keys.
So I'm gonna CLIck on my username, Stephane,
and I'm gonna go under Security credentials.
I will scroll down and I will create an access key.
As you can see, there are some selection you need to do
and based on the selection I'm doing, for example,
I want access key for the CLI,
AWS is going to have an alternative recommended.
For example, for the CLI, it's better to use CloudShell,
which I will show you in the next lecture.
So don't worry about it.
Or to use the CLI V2 and an authentication
through the IAM Identity Center, which I will not show you
because it's a bit more complicated.
So based on what you wanna do,
if it's local code, application running outside
of AWS or in AWS and so on,
you will have some recommendation in the bottom.
For now, we're going to use the CLI
and we'll use these access keys
and we'll click here to say
I understand the above recommendation
and I still want to create an access key
because it is important for you to understand how they are,
how they work, what they are, and so on.
So let's create this access key
and now this is the only time you'll be able to have access
to the access key and the secret access key.
So I will go back now to a previous version
of that lecture where you see the old UI, but don't worry,
nothing changes from that point on.
The first thing I have to do is to configure my AWS CLI.
So I'm going to type aws configure,
and then I am greeted with entering my access key ID.
Very nice. I can just enter this one and press Enter.
And then I'm greeted with entering my secret access key,
which I will enter right here as well.
The default region name.
So this is a region that is close to you.
I will choose eu-west-1
because I will be doing all my tutorials in eu-west-1
but you will choose your own region
and you can enter your own region name.
The region name, by the way,
you can get directly from this dropdown right here.
It shows you the name of the region,
as well as the region code.
So for me, I'm going to use my eu-west-1.
I'll press Enter and then the default output format.
I'll just press Enter as well.
So now my AWS CLI is configured
and so we can have a look at how it works.
We can do aws iam list-users and press Enter.
And this will list all the users in my accounts.
And as we can see,
the user I have right now is called Stephane.
Here is the user ID, here is the ARN, when it was created
and when the password was last used,
which is very similar to what I would get
if I were to go into this UI right here.
So the management console and the CLI do provide
similar kind of information.
Next, I want to show you what happens
if we remove permissions from our users.
So I'm gonna go to admins
and I'm going to remove the Stephane user
from the group admin.
And so again, if I go back to my user Stephane,
it doesn't have any permissions.
And I did this obviously
with my root accounts, not the other accounts.
So now if I go into my UI and obviously refresh this page,
I'm going to get an error saying that yes,
I do not have the permissions to do this
but let's try to do the same thing with the CLI.
So we're going to do an iam list-users call
and we get no response because actually it was being denied.
So the CLI permissions are obviously going
to be the exact same
as the permissions you get from the IAM console.
So the takeaway from this lecture
is that you can access AWS using the management console
or using access key and secret access key
that you can configure and then use into the CLI.
So hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.
And obviously, do not forget to add your user back
into the group,
otherwise that would be horrible.
So I'm gonna go into groups, admins
and I'm going to add my Stephane user back into my group.
And now I am an administrator again.
So that's it. I will see you in the next lecture.